Akira Takezawa

Address: Indiranagar, Bengaluru, India - 560038 Contact: (+91) 9513313099 | akiratakezawa71@gmail.com Personal website: https://samurainote.github.io/ & Linkedin

DATA SCIENCE ASSOCIATES

Profound, Insightful and result driven Data Science Associates with sharp analytics skills and experience in E-commerce and Matching platform business domein. Highly motivated self-taught Machine Learning Engineer, with over 20 personal implementations of developping ML/DL model. Present area of research/development is Natural Language Processing. Also almni of Machine Learning bootcamp 2018 winter batch from Byte Academy in NY. Excells in Data Diagnosis from Business Contexts. Outstands in define the problem which should be focused, collaborate as a Team in English and Japanese.

AREA OF EXPERTISE:

Machine Learning | Natural Language Processing | Image Processing | Time-series Data Analytics | Relational Database | Business Analytics | Data Mining | Marketing KPI Management | Data Visualization | Data Presentation | Statistics |

PROJECTS / PUBLICATION _____

- Seq2Seq Automatic Encoder-Decoder for English Chatbot: https://bit.ly/2U5hEqk
- Collaborative Filtering with SVD for Book Recommender System: https://bit.ly/2UMtylN
- HR meets Machine Learning, "Who will Leave your Company in This Year?": https://bit.ly/2W52HBU
- Speech Recognition and Classification by using Convolutional Neural Network: https://bit.ly/2OkdJQU
- How Dimension of Data Changes in each Seq2Seq Neural Network Layer: https://bit.ly/2Hw8pth

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES _____

- Platforms: MacOS Mojave version 10.14.3
- Language: Core Python, R, HTML5, CSS3
- Libraries: Tensorflow, Keras, OpenCV, Chainer, Scikit-learn, Genism, NLTK, Scipy, Numpy, Seaborn
- Databases: MySQL, PostgreSQL

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Data Science Fellow / ML Bootcamp from NY Byte Academy in Bangalore, India, Descember 2018 - March 2019 I joined one of the most creditable Data Science Bootcamp from New York, which provides real industry-driven capstone courses for 3 months. We basically learn theory of Machine Learning in the morning, and in afternoon we implement several machine learning algorithm for real business problem, and finally conducted personal projects. The participants with diverse background, like from Software Engineer to Business Analyst, collaborates on the same Data Science Projects. The whole hands-on intensive course are led by industry experienced professinal who also has master degree from IIM.

What I learned:

- Object Oriented Programming and Advanced Python
- Data Structures and Algorithm
- Relational Database Management: MySQL, PostgreSQL
- Web scraping by selenium and beautifulsoup
- Machine Learning for Regression and Classification, Clustering Task
- · Recommendation System by using Collaborative Filtering
- Deep Learning for Image and Text Data

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - Akira Takezawa

Bussiness Analyst / Xvolve Inc. in Tokyo, Japan, July 2018 - November 2018

Manages all marketing strategy and metrics of the dating web service for upper-class Man and Woman called "Bachelor" in Japan. Try to get voiceless Insights from quantitative Data, and designed full User Experience from the customer acquisition to the paid user, and finally to the continuity. In addition, I defined suitable KPI for particular terms by giving careful research of other worldwide subscription business, operated web advertisement by data driven analysis, improved core matching algorithm.

Key Achievements:

- Improved Paid Conversion Rate by 10% through correlation analysis between paid user and demographical data or UX.
- Acomplished lowest CPA (custemer acquision cost) by analytical improvement of web advirtisment.
- Built A KPI Tracking Dashboard on google spreadsheet for team members which is automatically updated once per a week.

Data Analyst / Cospa Creation Co. in Tokyo, Japan, April 2017 - June 2018

The company, which operates one of the largest online drop shipping platform in Japan which is called "通販素材.com,". I conducted Data Mining on over 2000 our private products, mostly centering on interiors. Mixed both quantitative actual Sales Data Analysis and making hypotheses based on qualitative research on market trends or needs for product planning team. Exciting part of job was break down physical products into Variables like function or some SEO keyword which is also important element for sales result.

Key Achievements:

- Become A Sales Top Data Analysts at the first year among other analysts who joined the company in the same year.
- Built Hand-made Data Visualization Dashboard on microsoft excel for other Data Analysts to improve team productivity.
- Introduced SEO based product sales result Analysis to the team which wasn't used to have.

Official Certification _____

- IBM Data Science Bootcamp Certification from Jigsaw Academy in Balgalore, India
- Machine Learning / Deep Learning Bootcamp Almuni from Byte Academy in New York, US
- Toefl ibt 86

Academic Background _____

- Graduated from Machine Learning winter bootcamp of 2018 from Byte Academy in NY
- Economics Bachelor Degree of Economics, Hokkaido University: one of the top 5 uni in Japan
- Moka High School: entranced and graduated as the Top student.